Marilyn Pearl Gallery
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Exhibition Files, 1973-1992, Series 2:; (Boxes 4-5; 1.15 linear ft.)
  - The Severe and the Romantic: Geometric Humanism in American Painting, 1950s-1980s (December 10, 1985-January 4, 1986), 1985-1986 (Box 4, Folder 71)
    Tad Wiley
  - Michael Loew (1907-1985): Memorial Exhibition and Friends of Michael Loew (January 7-February 5, 1986), 1973-1986 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Bernard Chaet: Themes and Variations, 1942-1985 (February 8-March 8, 1986), 1986 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Clinton Hill: New Work (March 11-April 5, 1986), 1986 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Barbara Siegel: "City Dwellers" (April 8-May 10, 1986), 1986 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Leo Rabkin: Relief Pastels (May 13-June 7, 1986), 1986 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Figurative Sculpture: The 80s (June 10-July 31, 1986), 1966-1986 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    Robert Arneson
    Nancy Bowen
    Natalie Charkow
    Philip Grausman
    Marisol
    Richard McDermott Miller
    Manuel Neri
    Linda Peer
  - Henry Pearson: Paintings (September 16-October 11, 1986), 1986 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Tenth Anniversary Exhibition: Sculptures by Mary Frank, Pat Lasch and Winifred Lutz (October 15-November 15, 1986), 1979-1987 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Linda Peer: Sculpture (November 18-December 13, 1986), 1986 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - George Constant: Fifty Years of Watercolor and Modern American Masters of Watercolor (December 16, 1986-January 10, 1987), 1986-1987 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    Milton Avery
    Nell Blaine
    Charles Demuth
    Sam Francis
    David Hockney
    John Marin
    Fairfield Porter
    Herman Rose
    Joseph Stella
  - Stephen Greene: 40th Anniversary Exhibition (January 13-February 7, 1987), 1986-1987 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - James Hennessey: First Paintings and Works on Paper (February 10-March 7, 1987), 1987 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Clinton Hill: Constructions and Paperworks (March 10-April 11, 1987), 1987 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Matt Phillips: "Garden Interludes": Collage-Monotypes (April 16-May 14, 1987), 1987 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Looking at the WPA: Mural Sketches and Other Works from the 1930s (May 19-June 20, 1987), 1985-1988 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    Will Barnet
    Isabel Bishop
    George Constant
    Stuart Davis
    Seymour Fogel
    Philip Guston
    Saul Levine
    Ben Shahn
    David Smith
    Stuyvesant Van Veen
  - [Inaugural Exhibition, 420 West Broadway] Michael Loew and Ellen Weiner (October 6-31, 1987), 1987 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Bernard Chaet: Paintings and Watercolors (November 3-28, 1987), 1987 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Henry Pearson: Three Decades and Group Show (December 1, 1987-January 9, 1988), 1987 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    Pat Lasch
  - Winifred Lutz: New Work (January 13-February 6, 1988), 1988 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Pedro Perez: New Work (February 9-March 5, 1988), 1988 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Clinton Hill: New Work (March 10-April 7, 1988), 1988 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - James Hennessey: New Work (April 9-May 5, 1988), 1988 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - American Exploration in Geometry: Color and Surface, 1950s and 1960s (June 7-July 1, 1988), 1988 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - New in New York: Summer Invitational (July 7-August 12, 1988), 1986-1988 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    Rodney Caswell
    Dan Gustin
    Didier Nolet
    Stephen Robin
  - Ellen Weiner (September 10-October 13, 1988), 1988 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Bud Hopkins (September 17-October 13, 1988), 1988 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Stephen Greene and Group Exhibition(October 15-November 10, 1988), 1988 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - William King: Sand and Plaster,1987-1988 and a Survey of Bronze, 1958-1988 (November 12-December 8, 1988), 1988-1989 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Jeanne Miles and Group Show (December 10, 1988-January 14, 1989), 1988 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    Robert Indiana
    Ward Jackson
    Bill King
  - Bernard Chaet: Small Paintings (January 11-February 4, 1989), 1989 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Leo Rabkin: Constructed Canvases, 1948-1988 (January 18-February 11, 1989), 1989 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Michael Loew: Early Work, 1929-1955 (February 15-March 11, 1989), 1988-1989 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Matt Phillips: Recent Collage Monotypes (March 15-April 8, 1989), 1989 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Kitty Klaidman: "Forest Memories" (April 1-27, 1989), 1989 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Stephen Robin: The Garden Series (April 12-May 6, 1989), 1989 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Clinton Hill: Woodcuts (April 29-May 27, 1989), 1989 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - James Hennessey: Recent Paintings (May 10-June 3, 1989), 1989 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Pedro Perez: Paintings and Sculpture, 1982-1987 (June 7-30, 1989), 1989 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - New Talent(July 6-August 3, 1989), 1989 (Box 5, Folder 39)
    Sandra Allen
    Jamie Fuller
    Jim McShea
    Franklin Shaw
    Walter Thompson
  - T. Wiley Carr (September 5-23, 1989), 1989 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Stephen Greene: Paintings and Drawings from the Sixties (September 27-October 24, 1989), 1963-1989 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - From Mondrian to Minimalism: American Constructivism, 1945-1965 (October 26-November 21, 1989), 1989 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Bernard Chaet: Twelve Years of Watercolor (November 24-December 22, 1989), 1989 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Didier Nolet: Oil Paintings and Watercolors (January 12-February 7, 1990), 1990 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Charmion von Wiegand (February 9-March 14, 1990), 1989-1990 (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Ironies: Figure and Still Life in Sculpture (March 16-April 14, 1990), 1990 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Clinton Hill: Collages of the 1950s and Constructions and Paper (April 18-May 16, 1990), 1990 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Winifred Lutz: "Correspondences" (May 18-July 30, 1990), 1990 (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Yale Faculty Show In Honor of Bernard Chaet (September 11-29, 1990), 1990 (Box 5, Folder 49)
    Mel Bochner
    Andrew Forge
    Jack Tworkov
  - Pat Lasch: New Sculpture (Oct. 5-27, 1990), 1990 (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Michael Loew: Paintings and Drawings, 1960s-1970s (October 32-November 24, 1990), 1990 (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - Leo Rabkin: Recent Works: Painted Paper Construction (November 28, 1990-January 5, 1991), 1990 (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Ellen Weiner: New Paintings (January 3-26, 1991), 1991 (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Jim McShea: Paintings (January 20-February 27, 1991), 1991 (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - Post-War Geometric Concepts 1945-1990 (March 6-April 6, 1991), 1989-1991 (Box 5, Folder 55)
    Stephen Ellis
    Kenneth Noland
    Robert Ryman
    Carey Smith
    Andrew Spence
    Gary Stephan
  - Peter Perez (April 10-May 4, 1991), 1991 (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - Henry Pearson: A Forty Year Survey (May 5-June 1, 1991), 1976-1991 (Box 5, Folder 57)
  - Nancy Davidson and Steven Dicillo (June 5-July 10, 1991), 1990-1991 (Box 5, Folder 58)
  - Bernard Chaet and Group Show (September 11-October 12, 1991), 1978-1991 (Box 5, Folder 59)
    Jean Arp
    Oscar Bluemner
    Charles Burchfield
    Jean Dubuffet
    Alberto Giacometti
    Mark Tobey
  - Michael Loew: Paintings and Drawings, 1940s-1950s (October 16-November 16, 1991), 1991 (Box 5, Folder 60)
  - James Hennessey: Paintings (November 20-December 21, 1991), 1991 (Box 5, Folder 61)
  - American Abstract Artists: Paintings and Drawings, 1930s, 1940s, 1950s (January-February, 1992), 1977-1992 (Box 5, Folder 62)
    Werner Drewes
    John Ferren
    A. E. Gallatin
    Gertrude Greene
    Carl Holty
    Irene Rice Pereira
    Louis Shanker
    Charles Shaw
    Esphyr Slobodkina
    Jean Xceron
  - Clinton Hill: Constructions, Hand Made Paper Assemblages, Furniture (March 5-April 11, 1992), 1992 (Box 5, Folder 63)
  - Didier Nolet: New Paintings and Pastels and Group Show (April 24-May 23, 1992), 1992 (Box 5, Folder 64)
    Sonia Delaunay
    Gertrude Green
    Irene Rice Perira
  - American Geometric Abstraction (May 28-July 3, 1992), 1992 (Box 5, Folder 65)
  - Ellen Weiner: "Rose and Compass Rose" (September 9-October 3, 1992), 1992 (Box 5, Folder 66)
  - Geometric Strategies and Henry Pearson: Early Works (October 8-November 14, 1992), 1992 (Box 5, Folder 67)
    Rene Pierre Allain
    Hillary Helfant
    Gary Lang
    Bruno Rousselot
    David Row
    K. Tsujimura
  - Sonia Delaunay and Charmion von Wiegand: Works on Paper and Winifred Lutz: Recent Prints (November 5-December 1992), 1992 (Box 5, Folder 68)
  - Hui Ka Kwong (December 1992), 1992 (Box 5, Folder 69)
- Business Records, 1976-2000, Series 3:; (Boxes 5-8; 2.65 linear ft.)
  Business records are arranged alphabetically by folder title. They document the mostly routine affairs of the gallery. Included are: client correspondence, inventory cards (work in stock, pieces returned to artists, and works sold), a nearly complete set of invoices for gallery sales for the period 1976-1986, consignment records, appraisals, exhibition schedules, mailing lists, guest books, and calendars. Also included are records regarding Marilyn Pearl's participation in the Basel Art Fairs of 1989-1993, and small amounts of correspondence concerning her activities as a private dealer after she closed her gallery.
  The folder titled "Gallery Publicity" contains articles about Marilyn Pearl and exterior photographs of West 57th Street, where Marilyn Pearl Gallery operated from 1976-1987.
  - Appraisals, 1980-1992, (2 folders) (Box 5, Folder 70-71)
  - Artist Biographies, circa 1991 (Box 5, Folder 72)
  - Artist Guidelines, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 73)
  - Artist Lists, 1983, undated (Box 5, Folder 74)
  - Basel Art Fair (1989) (Box 5)
    - Correspondence; Customs; Printed Material, 1988-1989 (Box 5, Folder 75)
    - Correspondence (Artpak Transport Ltd. problem), 1989 (Box 5, Folder 76)
    - Notes, Receipts, Names and Addresses, Photographs, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 77)
  - Basel Art Fair (1990) (Box 5)
    - Correspondence, 1989-1990 (Box 5, Folder 78)
    - Customs, Printed Material, 1989-1990 (Box 5, Folder 79)
    - Notes, Receipts, Names and Addresses, Photographs, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 80)
  - Basel Art Fair (1991) (Box 6)
    - Correspondence, Customs, 1990-1991 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Notes, Names and Addresses, Printed Material, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Basel Art Fair (1991)-Invoices, Receipts, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Basel Art Fair (1992), 1991-1992 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Basel Art Fair (1993), 1992-1993 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Bills Paid, 1987-1991, (6 folders) (Box 6, Folder 6-11)
  - Calendar, 1989, (1 vol.) (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Calendar, 1990, (1 vol.) (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Client Correspondence, 1989-1996 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Consignments, 1989-1996 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Delaunay, Sonia (purchase, consignments, research), 1991-1997, undated (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Exhibition Schedules, 1983-1992 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Gallery Publicity, circa 1982-1987, 1991-1992 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Guest Register (January-July), 1990 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Inventory Cards-Stock (all media) (Box 6)
    - Chaet, Bernard-Lasch, Pat, 1991-1992 (Box 6, Folder 20)
      Chaet, Bernard
      Greene, Stephen
      Hill, Clinton
      Hopkins, Budd
      Lasch, Pat
    - Loew, Michael, 1991-1992 (Box 6, Folder 21-23)
    - Lutz, Winifred-Pearson, Henry, 1991-1992 (Box 6, Folder 24)
      Lutz, Winifred
      Pearson, Henry
    - Pearson, Henry, 1991-1992, (2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 25-26)
    - Perez, Pedro-Weiner, Ellen; Non-Gallery Artists, 1991-1992 (Box 6, Folder 27)
      Perez, Pedro
      von Wiegand, Charmion
      Weiner, Ellen
      Non-Gallery Artists (Ives, Norman; Siegel, Barbara)
  - Inventory Cards-Returned to Artist (Box 7)
    - Carr, T. Wiley-Chaet, Bernard, 1990-1992 (Box 7, Folder 1)
      Carr, T. Wiley
    - Chaet, Bernard, 1990-1992 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Greene, Stephen, 1990-1992, (2 folders) (Box 7, Folder 3-4)
    - Hennessey, James-Hill, Clinton, 1990-1992 (Box 7, Folder 5)
      Hennessey, James
    - Hill, Clinton-Lutz, Winifred, 1990-1992 (Box 7, Folder 6)
      King, William
      Loew, Michael
    - McShea, Jim-Perez, Pedro, 1989-1992 (Box 7, Folder 7)
      McShea, Jim
      Miles, Jeanne
      Peer, Linda
    - Rabkin, Leo-Weiner, Ellen, 1990-1992 (Box 7, Folder 8)
      Rabkin, Leo
      Robin, Stephen
  - Inventory Cards-Sold (Box 7)
    - Carr, T. Wiley-Hennessey, James, 1984-1994 (Box 7, Folder 9)
      Constant, George
      Diller, Burgoyne
    - Hill, Clinton, 1985-1990 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Hockney, David-Nolet, Didier, 1981-1992 (Box 7, Folder 11)
      Hockney, David
      Klaidman, Kitty
      Noguchi, Isamu
      Nolet, Didier
    - Pearson, Henry-Weiner, Ellen, 1984-1992 (Box 7, Folder 12)
      Stella, Frank
  - Mailing Lists, 1990-1992, (3 folders) (Box 7, Folder 13-15)
  - Noguchi, Isamu (sale to Arnold Herstand and Co.; research), 1988-1989 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Resale Certificates and Related Correspondence, 1983-1992, undated (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Sales Records (Box 8)
    - Invoices, #1-100, October 2, 1976-May 10, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Invoices, #101-200, May 12, 1978-July 25, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Invoices, #201-300, July 31, 1979-January 28, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Invoices, #301-400, February 2, 1981-October 22, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Invoices, #402-500, October 23, 1982-May 9, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Invoices, #501-600, May 8, 1984-November 20, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Invoices, #601-699, November 22, 1985-December 8, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Invoices, #701-800, December 18, 1986-December 18, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Victoria Miro Gallery (Ofili diptych purchase), 2000 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Zabriskie Gallery, 1986-1993 (Box 8, Folder 10)